精神病患者
美亚利桑那州  凤凰城
12月11日  星期五
下午2点43分
你从没好好吃过午饭
You never did eat your lunch, did you?
我该回办公室了
I better get back to the office.
晚了老板会不高兴的
These extended lunch hours give my boss excess acid.
为什么不给他个电话
Why don't you call your boss and tell him
直接请一下午的假
You're taking the rest of the afternoon off?
反正是礼拜五  天又这么热
Friday anyway, and hot.
下午要是有空  我走着送你去机场吗
What do I do with my free afternoon? Walk you to the airport?
我们可以在这儿多快活一会儿
Well, we could laze around here a while longer.
3点就该退房了
Checking-out time is 3:00 pm.
这种档次的旅店  客人进来没人管
Hotels of this sort aren't interested in you when you come in,
可一旦时间到了...
But when your time is up...
萨姆  我讨厌和你在这样的地方偷偷摸摸
Oh, Sam, I hate having to be with you in a place like this.
听人家说  有些夫妻会故意
I've heard of married couples who deliberately spend
找廉价小旅店尝尝鲜
An occasional night in a cheap hotel.
结了婚当然想干嘛就干嘛了
When you're married you can do a lot of things deliberately.
你说话语气  太像结过婚的了
You sure talk like a girl who's been married.
萨姆  这是最后一次
Oh, Sam, this is the last time.
最后一次什么
Yeah? For what?
这一切
For this.
偷偷摸摸  私下幽会
For meeting you in secret so we can be secretive.
你来这儿出差  和我午间作乐
You come down here on business trips, and we steal lunch hours.
我甚至希望你没出现过
I wish you wouldn't even come.
好啊  那我们怎么联络感情呢
All right. What do we do instead?
写肉麻情书吗
Write each other lurid love letters?
萨姆  我得走了
Oh, I have to go, Sam.
下周我还能来
I can come down next week.
不要
No.
见你一面都不行吗
Not even just to see you?
吃顿正经的午饭怎么样
Have lunch, in public?
可以见面  吃晚饭也成
Oh, we can see each other. We can even have dinner.
但要很体面
But respectably.
在我家   对着我妈妈的照片
In my house, with my mother's picture on the mantel
我姐和我们一起烤3份牛肉
And my sister helping me broil a big steak for three.
那吃完牛肉之后
And after the steak,
让你姐去看电影  把你妈妈的照片扣过去怎么样
Do we send sister to the movies, turn Mama's picture to the wall?
萨姆
Sam!
好吧
All right.
曼璐  无时无刻  我都想见你
Marion, whenever it's possible, I want to see you.
任何情况  大庭广众也行
And under any circumstances, even respectability.
大庭广众听起来像是儿戏
You make respectability sound disrespectful.
不  我说真的
Oh, no, I'm all for it.
那就要控制欲火  耐心地等待
It requires patience, temperance, a lot of sweating out.
否则  很难办到
Otherwise, though, it's just hard work.
但如果能像现在这样见你爱抚你
But if I can see you and touch you, even as simply as this,
我无所谓
I won't mind.
我讨厌为不在的人卖命
I'm tired of sweating for people who aren't there.
我辛辛苦苦为老头子还债
I sweat to pay off my father's debts,
而他却躺在坟墓里
And he's in his grave.
我辛辛苦苦付给前妻生活费
I sweat to pay my ex-wife alimony,
她却住在地球另一边的什么鬼地方
And she's living on the other side of the world somewhere.
我也花钱呀
I pay, too.
住旅馆不也得花钱吗
They also pay who meet in hotel rooms.
过几年  债务还清了
A couple of years my debts will be paid off.
如果我前妻再婚  生活费也不用给了
If she ever remarries, the alimony stops.
我连一次婚都没结过
I haven't even been married once yet.
要是真结了婚  你就不这么想了
Yeah. But when you do, you'll swing.
萨姆  我们结婚吧
Oh, Sam, let's get married.
行啊  想和我混菲尔威尔五金店后仓库吗
And live with me in a storeroom behind a hardware store in Fairvale?
很搞笑的  跟你讲啊
We'll have lots of laughs. I'll tell you what.
我给前妻寄生活费  你得帮我贴邮票
When I send my ex-wife her alimony, you can lick the stamps.
我会贴邮票的
I'll lick the stamps.
曼璐  你要打消这念头
Marion, you want to cut this off,
还是找个合适的人吧
Go out and find yourself somebody availabIe?
我正在想这事呢
I'm thinking of it.
你怎么会想这事
How could you even think a thing like that?
别误了飞机
Don't miss your plane.
一起走  不行吗
Hey, we can leave together, can't we?
我已经晚了  而你还没穿上鞋呢
I'm late and you have to put your shoes on.
罗沃利老板吃午饭回来了吗
Is Mr. Lowery back from lunch?
他陪哈里斯街投资商吃午饭了
He's lunching with the man who's buying the Harris Street property.
就是那位石油租赁商  所以还没回来
You know, the oil lease man. That's why he's late.
你头疼?
You got a headache?
一会儿就好
It'll pass.
头疼就像决心
Headaches are like resolutions,
忘了它就没事了
You forget them as soon as they stop hurting.
你有阿司匹林吗
Have you got some Aspirin?
我有一种药  但不是阿司匹林
I've got something, not Aspirin.
结婚那天我妈的医生给的
My mother's doctor gave them to me the day of my wedding.
泰迪发现我吃止疼片很生气
Teddy was furious when he found out I'd taken tranqullizers.
有电话吗
Any calls?
泰迪打给我  我妈打来看泰迪是否打给我
Teddy called me. My mother called to see if Teddy called.
你姐打电话说要去图森买东西
Oh, your sister called to say she's going to Tucson to do some buying
还说她整个周末不回家了
And she'll be gone the whole weekend and...
真他妈的热
It's as hot as fresh milk.
小姐们  快让老板给你们装冷气机
Hey, you girls ought to get your boss to air condition you up.
他今天发财了
He can afford it today.
曼璐
Marion,
-拿文件给卡西迪先生看看  -好的
- Will you get the copies of that deed ready for Mr. Cassidy?  - Yes, sir.
明天是我心肝宝贝的大日子
Tomorrow's the day, my sweet little girl.
不是你  是我家闺女
Oh, not you. My daughter.
我的宝贝
A baby.
明天她要甜甜蜜蜜地
And tomorrow she stands her sweet self
嫁给别人当老婆啦
Up there and gets married away from me.
给你看她的照片
I want you to take a look at my baby.
18岁啦
Eighteen years old
从小到大她从没不开心过
And she never had an unhappy day in any one of those years.
别扯了  汤姆  我办公室可凉快了
Come on, Tom. My office is air conditioned.
知道我怎么哄她开心的吗
Do you know what I do about unhappiness?
我把不开心都买去了
I buy it off.
你...你不开心吗
Are...are you unhappy?
偶尔吧
Not inordinately.
我送这套房子给闺女当嫁妆
I'm buying this house for my baby's wedding present.
4万块现金
$40,000 cash.
有钱能使鬼推磨
Now that's not buying happiness.
花这点儿钱只图大家乐呵
That's just buying off unhappiness.
一般我是带多少花多少
I never carry more than I can afford to lose.
数数
Count them!
我的天啊
I declare!
这就是我的花钱之道
I don't. That's how I get to keep it.
汤姆  直接付这么多现金不合程序
Tom, a cash transaction of this size is most irregular.
那又怎样  买卖就是你情我愿
So what? It's my private money. Now it's yours.
为何不先安放好这笔钱
Suppose we put it in the safe,
周一早上如果你感觉好点...
And then Monday morning when you're feeling good...
说到感觉好点
Oh, speaking of feeling good,
你念叨的桌子里的那瓶酒呢
Where's that bottle you said was in your desk?
我偶尔才大嘴巴的
You know, sometimes I can keep my mouth shut.
罗沃利  我他妈太馋那瓶酒了
Lowery, I am dying of thirst aroonie.
这钱可不能放在办公室里
I don't even want it in the office over the weekend.
周末前赶紧存到银行保险柜里
Put it in the safe deposit box in the bank,
周一再让他确认一下
And we'll get him to give us a check on Monday instead.
好的
Yes.
乔治・罗沃利私人办公室
他一直调戏你呢
He was flirting with you.
他一定注意到我的结婚戒指了
I guess he must've noticed my wedding ring.
进来
Come in.
老板  给您文件  可以的话
The copies Mr. Lowery, if you don't mind,
我想去完银行直接回家
I'd like to go right on home after the bank.
-我头有点晕...  -直接回家吧  宝贝儿
- I have a slight... - You go right on home.
你老板和我正要出去呢
Because me and your boss are going out
接着喝酒去  对吧
And get ourselves a little drinking done. Right?
当然  不舒服吗
Of course. Do you feel ill?
头有点儿疼
Just a headache.
你该去拉斯维加斯度个周末
What you need is a weekend in Las Vegas,
那儿可是世界的乐园
The playground of the world.
我在家休养两天就好了  谢谢
I'm going to spend this weekend in bed. Thank you.
不吃点儿药吗  对付头疼可管用了
Aren't you going to take the pills? They'll knock that headache out.
药片换不来开心
Can't buy off unhappiness with pills.
去银行存完钱后
I guess I'll go put this money in the bank
我要回家睡上一觉
And then go home and sleep it off.
曼璐  怎么回事  你来这儿干什么
Marion, what in the world, what are you doing up here?
当然啦  见到你我好开心  一直都是啊
Of course I'm glad to see you, I always am,
曼璐  这是什么
What is it, Marion?
先停下
Hold it there.
您很赶时间啊
In quite a hurry.
对  我本想打个盹儿的
Yes. I didn't intend to sleep so long.
昨晚太困了  差点没撞车
I almost had an accident last night from sleepiness,
于是就在这儿停会儿
So I decided to pull over.
您在这儿过了一整晚吗
You slept here all night?
对  我说了  实在是太困了
Yes. As I said, I couldn't keep my eyes open.
附近有好多汽车旅馆  您可以...
There are plenty of motels in this area. You should've...
我是说  那儿更安全
I mean, just to be safe.
我没打算睡一整晚的  只想停一小会儿
I didn't intend to sleep all night. I just pulled over.
我违法了吗
Have I broken any laws?
没有  女士
No, Ma.am.
那我可以走了吗
Then I'm free to go?
您遇到什么麻烦了吗
Is anything wrong?
当然没有  我像是遇到麻烦的人吗
Of course not. Am I acting as if there's something wrong?
说实话  很像
Frankly, yes.
拜托   我得走了
Please, I'd like to go.
真的没有吗
Well, is there?
您什么意思
Is there what?
跟您说过了  我没遇到什么麻烦
I've told you there's nothing wrong,
就是很着急  而您正在耽误我的时间
Except that I'm in a hurry and you're taking up my time.
再等等  先别启动
Now, just a moment. Turn your motor off, please.
可以看下您的驾照吗
May I see your license?
为什么
Why?
请出示
Please.
请您稍等片刻
Be with you in a second!
-我没心情找麻烦  -什么
- I'm in no mood for trouble. - What?
俗话说的好
There's an old saying. ..
第一位顾客总是最麻烦
The first customer of the day is always the most trouble...
我说了  不想找麻烦
But like I say, I'm in no mood for it,
我直接实在点儿  包您满意
So I'm gonna treat you so fair and square that you won.
我有理由...
I have one human reason...
可以用我的车换吗
Can I trade my car in and take another?
秃子头上长虱子  明摆着  可以
Do anything you have a mind to being a woman, you will.
那辆是您的吗
That yours?
对  车本身没有任何毛病
Yes, it's... There's nothing wrong with it.
-我只是...  -有点儿看腻了
- I just... - Sick of the sight of it.
那您随便看看
Why don't you have a look around here
挑辆中意的
And see if there's something that strikes your eyes.
然后我让机械师给您做个一站式维护
And meanwhile, I'll have my mechanic give yours the once-over.
-想喝点儿咖啡吗  我正打算...  -不  谢谢
- You want some coffee? I was just about... - No, thank you.
我很急  只想换辆车
I'm in a hurry and I just wanna make a change.
一般来讲  买完二手车
One thing people never ought to be
急着走的肯定有问题
When they're buying used cars and that's in a hurry.
不过我说了  天气好不吵架
But like I said, it's too nice a day to argue.
我先把您的车开到车库里
I'll shoot your car in the garage here.
我为你推荐这款
That's the one I'd have picked for you myseIf.
-多少钱  -先试试吧
- How much? - Go ahead.
上街跑两圈
Spin it around the block.
看起来不错
It looks fine.
我的车外加多少钱卖
How much would it be with my car?
您不想试试车  考虑一两天吗
You mean you don't want the usual day and a half to think it over?
您真是很急呀  有人追您吗
You are in a hurry, aren't you? Somebody chasing you?
当然没有  说个价吧
Of course not. Please.
遇到顾客这么为难售车员真是头一次呀
Well, it's the first time the customer ever high pressured the salesman.
大概算一下
I figure roughly
算上原先的的车您给700块吧
Your car plus $700.
700块
$700
您还是会花点时间讲价的  对吧
You always got time to argue money, huh?
行
All right.
我希望您证明下那车的确是您的
I take it you can prove that car is yours.
我是说联邦驾照  车辆所有权证明
I mean, out-of-state license and all. You got your pink slip...
-我确定手续齐备  -有卫生间吗
- I believe I have the necessary papers. - Is there a ladies room?
在楼里面
In the building.
那边
Over there.
我希望您先试一下车
I think you better take it for a trial spin.
我不想败坏加州查理(二手车商)的名声
I don't want any bad word of mouth about California Charlie.
我看没必要吧
I'd really rather not.
我们就不能马上交易然后...
Can't we just settle this and...
女士  跟您说实话
I might as well be perfectly honest with you, Ma.am.
不是我不相信您  不过...
It's not that I don't trust you, but...
不过什么
But what?
因为赶时间  看好了就付钱
Is there anything so terribly wrong
有什么严重问题吗
About making a decision and wanting to hurry?
您认为那车是我偷的吗
Do you think I've stolen my car?
不是那意思  女士
No, Ma.am.
好吧  我们进去谈
All right, let's go inside.
放里面就行了
Just put it in here, please.
谢谢
Thank you.
加州查理: 见鬼了  警官
California Charlie's voice, heck, officer,
第一次遇到这样的顾客
That was the first time I ever saw the customer
这么为难售车员的
High pressure the salesman,
警察: 有人追她吗
Officer,' Somebody chasing her?
查理  让我看下她的文件
I better have a look at those papers, Charlie,
加州查理: 您看她有问题吗
Callfornia Charlie,' She look like a wrong one to you?
警察: 有点儿可疑
Officer,' Acted like one,
加州查理: 最可笑的是
Callfornia Charlie,' The only funny thing,
她还付给我700块现金呢
She paid me $700 in cash
卡洛琳: 是的  罗沃利老板
Caroline,' Yes, Mr. Lowery,
罗沃利: 卡洛琳  曼璐还没来吗
Lowery,' Caroline, Marion still isn't in?
卡洛琳: 还没有  老板
Caroline,' No, Mr. Lowery,
不过周一早上她总会晚到一会儿
But then she's always a bit late on Monday mornings,
罗沃利: 她来了马上给我打电话
Lowery,' buzz me the minute she comes in,
给她姐打电话  家里电话没人接
And call her sister, no one's answering at the house,
卡洛琳: 罗沃利老板  她姐姐单位我打过了
Caroline,' I called her sister, Mr. Lowery, where she works,
就是那家音乐大师音像店
The Music Makers Music Store, you know,
和我们一样  她也不知道曼璐在哪儿
And she doesn't know where Marion is any more than we do,
罗沃利: 你最好去她家看看
Lowery,' you better run out to the house,
她可能在家  但没法接电话
She may be, well, unable to answer the phone,
卡洛琳: 她姐姐也正打算回家呢  和我们一样着急
Caroline,' her sister's going to do that, she's as worried as we are,
罗沃利: 我真是搞不明白
Lowery,' no, I haven't the faintest idea,
我最后看见你妹妹  是上周五办公室里
As I said, I last saw your sister when she left this office on Friday,
她说不舒服想早点下班
She said she didn't feel well and wanted to leave early,
我允许了
And I said she could,
那是最后一面  等等
That was the last I saw, oh, wait a minute,
我过一会儿又见到她了  开着车...
I did see her some time later, driving,,,
你最好赶紧来我办公室一趟
I think you'd better come over here to my office, quick,
卡洛琳  请卡西迪先生过来
Caroline, get Mr. Cassidy for me,
罗沃利: 卡西迪  跟你说过  那么多现金不安全
After all, Cassidy, I toId you, all that cash!
我没有什么责任
I'm not taking the responsiblity,
卡西迪: 去他娘的
Cassidy,' Oh, for heaven's sake,
她给你当了10年差  你那么信任她
A girl works for you for 10 years, you trust her,
罗沃利: 好了  你最好来一趟
All right, yes, you better come over,
卡西迪: 我可不想4万块就这么打水漂了
Cassidy,' Well, I ain't about to kiss off $40,000!
我得把钱找回来  一个子儿都不能少
I'll get it back, and if any of it's missing,
钱要是没了有她好看  臭娘们儿
I'll replace it with her fine, soft flesh!
我要抓住她  不管你怎么想
I'll track her, never you doubt it,
罗沃利: 且慢  卡西迪
Lowery,' hold on, Cassidy,
我还是不能相信  其中定有蹊跷  我不能...
I still can't belleve. It must be some kind of a mystery, I can't...
卡西迪: 你不是去银行查过了吗
You checked with the bank, no?
他们不是从没见过她吗
They never laid eyes on her, no?
你到底信她什么  老天爷呀
You still trusting? Hot creepers!
我大大咧咧掏钱的时候她就坐在那儿
She sat there while I dumped it out!
眼皮都没抬几下  暗自盘算着
Hardly even looked at it, planning,
甚至还和我眉来眼去
And even flirting with me!
贝茨汽车旅馆  仍有空房
抱歉  雨太大我没听到您叫门
Gee, I'm sorry I didn't hear you in all this rain.
请进来吧
Go ahead in, please.
风尘仆仆啊
Dirty night.
有空房吗
You have a vacancy?
总共12间  间间都空着呢
Oh, we have 12 vacancies. Twelve cabins, 12 vacancies.
高速...转道了
They... They moved away the highway.
我还以为已经下高速了呢
Oh, I thought I'd gotten off the main road.
早料到了
I knew you must have.
谁没事愿在这儿停车呢
Nobody ever stops here anymore unless they've done that.
不过我们没感觉有什么损失
But there's no sense dwelling on our losses.
照常点灯  照常营业
We just keep on lighting the lights and following the formallties.
玛丽・萨米尔
Marie Samuels
您的家庭地址  填下镇名就行了
Your home address. Oh, just the town will do.
洛杉矶
Los Angeles.
1号房  需要什么服务随叫随到
Cabin one. It's closer in case you want anything.
就在服务台旁边
Right next to the office.
我就想好好睡一觉  再吃点儿东西
I want sleep more than anything else, except maybe food.
沿路朝前10里左右有家大馆子
Well, there's a big diner about 10 miles up the road,
就在菲尔威尔城外
Just outside of Fairvale.
这儿离菲尔威尔那么近啊
Am I that close to Fairvale?
15里  我去拿您的行李
Fifteen miles. I'll get your bags.
天啊  里面真闷
Boy, it's stuffy in here.
垫子很软
Well, the mattress is soft
衣服可以挂在衣柜里
And there's hangers in the closet and
还有印有贝茨汽车旅馆的文具
Stationery with bates motel printed on it
可以带回家给您的朋友炫耀一下
In case you wanna make your friends back home feel envious.
还有那什么...
And the...
在那儿
Over there.
盥洗室
The bathroom.
如果您有需要  就敲一下墙
Well, if you want anything, just tap on the wall.
-我就在服务台  -谢谢您  贝茨先生
- I'll be in the office. - Thank you, Mr. Bates.
诺曼・贝茨
Norman Bates.
您不会是打算开车去吃晚饭吧
You're not really gonna go out again and drive up to the diner, are you?
是啊
No.
那您愿意帮我个忙吗  和我吃个晚饭怎么样
Well, then would you do me a favor? Would you have dinner with me?
我就一个人
I was just about to myseIf.
没什么特别的  只有三明治和牛奶
You know, nothing special, just sandwiches and milk.
如果你能来  我会非常高兴的
But I'd like it very much if you'd come up to the house.
我餐桌并不豪华  但厨房却很温馨
I don't set a fancy table, but the kitchen's awful homey.
-我很乐意  -好的
- I'd like to. - All right.
你自己收拾一下  脱掉湿靴子
You get yourself settled and take off your wet shoes,
我准备好了就叫你
And I'll be back as soon as it's ready.
好的
Okay.
我会...打伞来接你
With my... with my trusty umbrella.
不行  我告诉你  不行
No! I tell you no!
我不能让你带陌生年轻女孩来吃饭
I won't have you bringing strange young girls in for supper!
烛光晚餐  这种低俗色情的方式
By candlelight, I suppose, in the cheap, erotic fashion
来自于年轻人低俗色情的心理
Of young men with cheap, erotic minds!
母亲  别这样
Mother, please.
然后呢  晚餐后呢  音乐?  情话?
And then what, after supper? Music? Whispers?
母亲  她只是个陌生人  饿着肚子  外面又在下雨
Mother, she's just a stranger. She's hungry and it's raining out.
母亲  她只是个陌生人...
...mother, she's just a stranger...
男人不该随便和不认识的女子来往...
As if men don't desire strangers. As if...
我不想再说这些令人反胃的事了  我觉得恶心
I refuse to speak of disgusting things, because they disgust me!
你明白了吗  孩子  去吧
You understand, boy? Go on.
告诉她  我做的饭和我儿子
Go tell her she'll not be appeasing her ugly appetite
都不会让她喜欢的
With my food or my son!
你没胆量的话  要我亲自去说吗
Or do I have to tell her 'cause you don't have the guts?
怎么样  孩子  你有没有胆量  孩子
Huh, boy? You have the guts, boy?
闭嘴  闭嘴
Shut up! Shut up!
我给你添麻烦了
I've caused you some trouble.
不
No.
母亲...我母亲
Mother... my mother...
怎么说呢
What is the phrase?
她今天心情不太好
She isn't quite herself today.
你不必麻烦了  我真的不饿
You shouldn't have bothered. I really don't have that much of an appetite.
我很抱歉
Oh, I'm sorry.
我希望能替她道歉
I wish you could apologize for other people.
不要紧
Don't worry about it.
不过既然你准备好了晚餐  我们一起吃吧
But as long as you've fixed a supper, we may as well eat it.
服务台那里会比较暖和
It might be nicer and warmer in the office.
雨停了
Well, it stopped raining.
服务台不太方便
Eating in an office is just too officious.
后面有个小房间
I have the parlor back here.
好的
All right.
请坐
Sit down.
谢谢
Thank you.
你真好
You're very kind.
都是你的  我不饿  你吃吧
It's all for you. I'm not hungry. Go ahead.
你...你吃东西的样子像只鸟
You... you eat like a bird.
你很了解它们
And you'd know, of course.
不  也不是
No, not really.
总之  我听说  跟鸟的吃相一样
Anyway, I hear the expression ..eats like a bird..
是不对...不对的
Is really a false... falsity.
因为鸟的食量很大
Because birds really eat a tremendous lot.
我对鸟的习性不是很了解
But I don't really know anything about birds.
我喜欢收集东西
My hobby is stuffing things.
比如标本
You know, taxidermy.
我想我比较喜欢鸟
And I guess I'd just rather stuff birds
因为我讨厌看到野兽做成的标本
Because I hate the look of beasts when they're stuffed.
像狐狸和人猿什么的
You know, foxes and chimps.
有些人甚至拿狗和猫做标本  我可做不到
Some people even stuff dogs and cats, but, oh, I can't do that.
我想只有鸟类标本比较好看  因为...
I think only birds look well stuffed because...
因为它们会和你培养出情感
Well, because they're kind of passive to begin with.
很奇怪的爱好  很稀奇
It's a strange hobby. Curious.
也很不寻常
Uncommon, too.
我想也是
Oh, I imagine so.
这并不如你想像的花钱  很便宜的
And it's not as expensive as you'd think. It's cheap, really.
只要有针线  苏打粉
You know, needles and thread, sawdust.
只要花钱买些化学品就可以了
The chemicals are the only thing that cost anything.
人应该有爱好的
A man should have a hobby.
这...这不只是爱好
Well, it's... It's more than a hobby.
爱好是用来消磨时间  而不是充实自己的
A hobby's supposed to pass the time, not fill it.
你感到空虚吗
Is your time so empty?
不
No.
我经营这家旅馆
Well, I run the office
打扫房间
And tend the cabins and grounds
帮我母亲做些
And do little errands for my mother.
她认为我可以做的事
The ones she allows I might be capable of doing.
你和朋友们出去吗
Do you go out with friends?
一个男孩最好的朋友就是他母亲
Well, a boy's best friend is his mother.
你一生中还从未有过空虚的时候吧
You've never had an empty moment in your entire life, have you?
一个人的时候会有
Only my share.
你要去哪里
Where are you going?
我不是要刺探你
I didn't mean to pry.
我在找一处没人去的地方
I'm looking for a private island.
你在逃避什么事情吗
What are you running away from?
为什么这么问
Why do you ask that?
人们总是在逃避事情
People never run away from anything.
雨下的时间不长  你知道我怎么想的吗
The rain didn't last long, did it? You know what I think?
我在想
I think that
我们都掉在自己的陷阱中
We're all in our private traps,
被它紧紧困住  没人爬得出来
Clamped in them, and none of us can ever get out.
我们想抓住什么东西
We scratch and claw,
但抓到的只是空气  只是陷阱
But only at the air, only at each other.
结果  没有一点进展
And for all of it, we never budge an inch.
有时候我们根本没掉入那些陷阱
Sometimes we deliberately step into those traps.
我掉进去了  我不在乎了
I was born in mine. I don't mind it anymore.
你应该在乎  应该在乎的
Oh, but you should. You should mind it.
我在乎  但我想说不在乎
Oh, I do, but I say I don't.
如果有人像你母亲对你那样
You know, if anyone ever talked to me the way I heard,
同我说话的话...
The way she spoke to you...
有时候当她那样对我说话时
Sometimes when she talks to me like that,
我真想上楼去咒骂她  永远离开她
I feel I'd like to go up there and curse her and leave her forever.
至少不会顺从她
Or at least defy her.
但我知道我不能这样
But I know I can't.
她病了
She's ill.
听她说话的声音很健康
She sounded strong.
不  她病了
No, I mean ill.
自从我父亲死后她扶养我到现在
She had to raise me all by herself, after my father died.
当时我才5岁  对她的打击很大
I was only five and it must've been quite a strain for her.
她不必出去工作
I mean, she didn't have to go to work or anything like that.
他给她留下了一点儿钱
He left her a little money.
几年前母亲遇到了一个男人
Anyway, a few years ago, mother met this man.
他说服她盖了这栋旅馆
And he talked her into building this motel.
他可以说服她干任何事
He could have talked her into anything.
当他也死后  对她的打击更大
And when he died, too, it was just too great a shock for her.
他死的样子...
And the way he died...
你吃饭时不应该说这些的
I guess it's nothing to talk about while you're eating.
总之  那对她是一大重创  她什么都没了
Anyway, it was just too great a loss for her. She had nothing left.
至少还有你啊
Except you.
儿子是替代不了爱人的
Well, a son is a poor substitute for a lover.
你为什么不离开呢
Why don't you go away?
像你一样  去一个没人的地方吗
To a private island, like you?
不  不是像我
No, not like me.
我不能那样  谁来照顾她呢
I couldn't do that. Who'd look after her?
她会很寂寞的
She'd be alone up there.
壁炉的火会灭的
Her fire would go out.
这里会寒冷得像座坟墓
It'd be cold and damp like a grave.
如果你爱某人
If you love someone,
即使你恨他  你也不会这样做
You don't do that to them, even if you hate them.
你知道吗  我不恨她
You understand, I don't hate her.
我只是恨她变成这个样子
I hate what she's become.
我恨她的病态
I hate the illness.
如果你把她安置在某处...
Wouldn't it be better if you put her
是不是比较好
Someplace...
你是说那个地方?  疯人院?
You mean an institution? A madhouse?
人们说的某处就是疯人院  不是吗
People always call a madhouse someplace, don't they?
把她安置在某处
Put her in someplace.
抱歉  我不是说不照顾她
I'm sorry. I didn't mean it to sound uncaring.
你对照顾知道多少
What do you know about caring?
你到那种地方去看过吗
Have you ever seen the inside of one of those places?
他们又哭又笑
The laughing and the tears
用阴冷的双眼观察你
And the cruel eyes studying you.
我的母亲去那种地方?
My mother there?
但她不会伤害别人
But she's harmless.
她不会伤害别人  就像那些标本鸟一样
She's as harmless as one of those stuffed birds.
对不起
I am sorry.
我只是觉得...她好像在伤害你
I only felt... It seems she's hurting you.
我没有恶意
I meant well.
人们总说没有恶意
People always mean well.
他们言辞温和  动作优雅
They cluck their thick tongues and shake their heads
建议正确  好像很优美一样
And suggest, oh, so very delicately.
当然  我自己也对自己建议过
Of course, I've suggested it myself.
但我讨厌这种想法
But I hate to even think about it.
她需要我
She needs me.
她并不是...
It's not as if she were
疯子或者精神错乱的人
A maniac, a raving thing.
只是有时候会神智不清
She just goes a little mad sometimes.
我们有时候也会神智不清
We all go a little mad sometimes.
你没有过吗
Haven't you?
有过
Yes.
但一次就够了
Sometimes just one time can be enough.
谢谢你
Thank you.
谢谢你  诺曼
Thank you, Norman.
诺曼
Norman.
你是不是要回房去了
Oh, you're not going back to your room already?
我很累
I'm very tired.
明天还要开车  回凤凰城
And I have a long drive tomorrow, all the way back to Phoenix.
是吗
Really?
我在那里闯了点祸
I stepped into a private trap back there
我要回去处理一下
And I'd like to go back and try to pull myself out of it
乘还来得及
Before it's too late for me, too.
你真的不想再多待一会儿吗
Are you sure you wouldn't like to stay just a little while longer?
只是聊聊天
Just for talk?
我很想  但是...
Oh, I'd like to, but...
好吧
All right.
那明天早晨再见
Well, I'll see you in the morning.
我会给你带点儿早点  好吗
I'll bring you some breakfast, all right?
什么时候走
What time?
很早  黎明吧
Very early. Dawn.
好  怎么称呼...
All right, miss...
克兰
Crane.
克兰  没错
Crane. That's it.
晚安
Good night.
不
No!
母亲  天哪  母亲
Mother! Oh, god, mother!
血  血
Blood! Blood!
我试过很多牌子
I've tried many brands.
到目前为止  我用过的似乎都没什么效果
So far, of those I've used, I haven't had much luck with any of them.
看看这个牌子怎么说
Let's see what they say about this one.
它说的那些成分
They tell you what its ingredients are
保证可以驱除所有蚊虫
And how it's guaranteed to exterminate every insect in the world,
但它没说是不是有痛苦
But they do not tell you whether or not it's painless.
我想  昆虫和人一样  希望没有痛苦地死去
And I say, insect or man, death should always be painless.
我想这个牌子的品质
I suppose, this one seems to claim more and better
应该比其他的好
Qualities than lots of the others.
萨姆?
Sam?
萨姆  有位女士找你
Sam! Lady wants to see you.
小姐  什么事
Yes, miss?
我是曼璐的姐姐
I'm Marion's sister.
是莱拉呀
Oh, sure. Lila.
曼璐在这里吗
Is Marion here?
当然不在
Well, of course not.
有什么事吗
Something wrong?
她星期五离开家
She left home on Friday.
我和孩子在图森度周末  那时我就没见到她
I was in Tucson over the weekend and I haven't heard from her since.
甚至没接到她的电话
Not even a phone call.
如果你们两个要在一起  我不会管
Look, if you two are in this thing together, I don't care,
这不关我的事
It's none of my business,
我要和曼璐谈  我要曼璐告诉我
But I want to talk to Marion and I want her to tell me
这不关我的事  然后我就走...
It's none of my business and then I'll go...
鲍伯  出去吃午餐吧
Bob, run out and get yourself some lunch, will you?
没关系  萨姆  我带了
That's okay, Sam. I brought it with me.
那就出去吃吧
Run out and eat it.
我们两个怎么会在一起
Now, what thing could we be in together?
对不起  我失态了
Sorry about the tears.
曼璐出事了吗  怎么回事
Well, is Marion in trouble? What is it?
我们一起来谈谈曼璐  好不好
Let's all talk about Marion, shall we?
你是谁  朋友
Who are you, friend?
我叫阿伯盖斯特  朋友
My name is Arbogast, friend.
私家侦探
I'm a private investigator.
她在哪里  克兰小姐
Where is she, Miss Crane?
我不认识你
I don't know you.
我知道你不认识我  因为如果你认识
Why, I know you don't, because if you did,
我就无法跟踪你了
I wouldn't be able to follow you.
你为什么要插手这事
What's your interest in this?
4万块钱
Well, $40,000.
-4万块钱?  -对
- $40,000? - That's right.
你们最好告诉我发生了什么事  快点说
Well, one of you'd better tell me what's going on, and tell me fast.
我实在无法忍受...
I can take just so much of this...
别激动  朋友
Now, take it easy, friend.
别激动  只是你的女朋友偷了4万块钱
Take it easy. It's just that your girlfriend stole $40,000.
你在说什么  到底怎么回事
What are you talking about? What is this?
她星期五本来该去银行存钱  但她没有
She was supposed to bank it on Friday for her boss and she didn't.
之后没有人再看到她
And no one has seen her since.
有人看到过她
Someone has seen her.
有人知道她有4万块钱
Someone always sees a girl with $40,000.
萨姆  他们不想控告  只希望把钱要回来
Sam, they don't want to prosecute, they just want the money back.
萨姆  假如她在这里...
Sam, if she's here...
她不在  她不在这里
She isn't. She isn't.
克兰小姐  可以问你个问题吗
Miss Crane, can I ask you a question?
你只是来这里而没有其他想法吗
Did you come up here on just a hunch and nothing more?
我根本没想到其他事  只是希望
Not even a hunch. Just hope.
等我们查证后  我就能相信你了
Well, with a little checking I could get to believe you.
我不在乎你是否相信我
I don't care if you believe me or not.
我只想在曼璐越陷越深之前找到她
All I want to do is see Marion before she gets in this too deeply.
你有没有去凤凰城的医院找
Did you check in Phoenix? Hospitals?
她可能出了车祸  或被抢劫
Maybe she had an accident, or a holdup.
不  有人看到她驾车离开市区
No, she was seen leaving town in her own car,
补充一下  是她老板看到的
By her employer, I might add.
我不敢相信  你呢
I can't believe it. Can you?
对于名声不好的人
Well, you know, we're always quickest to doubt people
我们都持怀疑态度
Who have a reputation for being honest.
我想她在这里  克兰小姐
I think she's here, Miss Crane.
她的这位男友...
Where there's a boyfriend...
可能并没有在幕后操纵
Well, she's not back there with the nuts and bolts,
但她一定在这里  在市区的某个地方
But she's here, in this town somewhere.
我会找到她  我会见到你的
I'll find her. I'll be seeing you.
-晚上好  -晚上好
- Evening. - Evening.
我刚才差一点儿在那里转弯
I almost drove right past.
我忘了把灯箱打开  我们有空房
I'm always forgetting to turn the sign on, but we do have a vacancy.
总共12间  间间都空着呢  吃糖
Twelve, in fact. Twelve cabins, twelve vacancies. Candy?
不  谢谢
No, thanks.
这两天我已经看了很多旅馆  眼都花了
Last two days, I've been to so many motels my eyes are bleary with neon,
这里是第一个
But, you know, this is the first place that
远离尘世的地方
Looks like it's hiding from the world.
说实话  我不是忘了把灯箱打开
Well, I'll tell you the truth. I didn't really forget to turn the sign on.
只是想让人以为这里很少人来
Just doesn't seem like any use anymore, you know.
那里本来是主干道
See, that used to be the main highway right there.
进来登记吧
Well, wanna come in and register?
不  不  你坐下  我不想麻烦你
No, no, sit down. I don't wanna trouble you.
只是想问你几个问题
I just wanna ask a few questions.
不  不麻烦  今天是换洗日
No, that's no trouble. Today's linen day.
我每周都把床铺清洗一下
I always change the beds here once a week
不管有没有人住
Whether they've been used or not.
你讨厌潮湿  对吧  那...
Hate the smell of dampness, don't you? It's such a...
我不知道  发臭了  进来吧
I don't know, creepy smell. Come on.
你想买栋旅馆吗
You out to buy a motel?
不是
No.
你刚才说这两天
Reason I ask, you said you'd seen so many
看了很多家旅馆  我在想你可能...
In the past couple of days, I thought maybe you...
你...你要问什么
What... What was it you wanted to ask?
我在找一个失踪的人
Well, you see, I'm looking for a missing person.
我叫阿伯盖斯特  私家侦探
My name's Arbogast. I'm a private investigator.
我一直在找一个女孩的下落
I've been trying to trace a girl
她在凤凰城失踪一个星期了
That's been missing for, oh, about a week now from Phoenix.
是家庭纠纷  他们已经原谅她了
It's a private matter. The family wants to forgive her.
她并没有任何麻烦
She's not in any trouble.
我想警察不会找没有惹麻烦的人
I didn't think the police went looking for people who aren't in trouble.
-我不是警察  -对啊
- I'm not the police. - Oh, yeah.
我们确信她走的是这条路
We have reason to believe that she came along this way.
可能在这附近停留过  她来过这里吗
May have stopped in the area. Did she stop here?
我们这儿好几个礼拜没人来了
Well, no one's stopped here for a couple of weeks.
你可不可以先看看照片再作证
Would you mind looking at the picture before committing yourself?
作证?
Commit myself?
你的口气真像警察
You sure talk like a policeman.
请认一下照片里的人
Look at the picture, please.
-确定吗  -确定
- Sure? - Yeah.
她可能用的是别名
Well, she may have used an alias.
曼璐・克兰才是她的真名
Marion Crane is her real name,
但她可能是用另一个名字登记的
But she could've registered under a different one.
老实讲  我甚至懒得再让客人登记
Well, I tell you, I don't even much bother with guests registering anymore.
慢慢地就不再拘泥于形式
You know, one by one, you drop the formalities.
我甚至不该费时去换床单
I shouldn't even bother changing the sheets,
然而积习难改
But old habits die hard.
这提醒了我...
Which reminds me...
那是什么
What's that?
旅馆的标志灯箱
It's the light. The sign.
上周有对夫妇说  如果那玩意儿没开着的话
We had a couple last week, said if the thing hadn't been on,
他们会以为这是间无人居住的旧...
They would've thought this was an old, deserted...
我也这么认为
Well, you see, that's exactly my point.
你说已经好几个礼拜没人来过这儿了
You said that nobody'd been here for a couple weeks,
还有对夫妇经过并不知道你在营业
And there's a couple came by and didn't know that you were open.
对
Yeah.
正如你所言  积习难改
Well, as you say, old habits die hard.
有可能这个女孩是用化名来登记的
It's possible, this girl could've registered under another name.
介意我看一下登记簿吗
Do you mind if I look at your book?
-不介意  -谢谢
- No. - Thank you.
好的
All right.
从日期查起
I'll get the date somewhere.
瞧见了吧  没有此人
See, there's nobody.
我有她的笔迹样本  来对照一下
Let's see now, I have a sample of her handwriting here.
找到了
Here we are.
玛丽・萨米尔  有趣的化名
Marie Samuels. That's an interesting alias.
是她吗
Is that her?
是的  我想是的
Yeah. Yeah, I think so.
玛丽  曼璐
Marie, Marion.
萨米尔  她男朋友叫萨姆
Samuels. Her boyfriend's name is Sam.
她是否有可能乔装打扮过?
Was she in disguise, by any chance?
要再确认一下照片吗
Wanna check the picture again?
听着  我并没有对你撒谎  先生...
Look, I wasn't lying to you, Mr...
我知道  我知道你没撒谎
Oh, I know that. I know you wouldn't lie.
时间久了记忆容易模糊
You know, it's tough keeping track of the time around here.
明白...
Oh, I know, I know.
记起来了
Oh, yeah.
那天下着雨
Well, it was raining
她的头发都湿透了
And her hair was all wet.
说实话  照片跟她本人真是相差甚远
I tell you, it's not really a very good picture of her either.
我想也是
No, I guess not.
跟我讲一下她吧
Tell me all about her.
那晚她来投宿已经相当晚了  所以直接就去睡了
She arrived rather late one night, and she went straight to sleep
第二天一早就退房了
And left early the next morning.
多早?
How early?
很早
Oh, very early.
哪天早上
Which morning was that?
第二天早上  是周日
The...The next morning. Sunday.
明白了
I see.
-有人跟她在这儿碰面吗  -没有
- Did anyone meet her here? - No.
有人跟她一起来吗
Did she arrive with anyone?
没有
No.
她有打过任何电话或是...
Did she make any phone calls or...
没有
No.
本地通话呢
Locally?
你跟她在一起过夜吗
Did you spend the night with her?
没有
No.
那你怎么知道她没打过电话
Well then, how would you know that she didn't make any phone calls?
她很累  然后...
Well, she was very tired and...
我开始记起来了
See, now I'm starting to remember.
我脑海里正在勾勒那个画面
I'm making a mental picture of it in my mind.
如果你勾勒某个画面...
You know, if you make a mental picturization of something...
好...慢慢想
That's right. That's right. Take your time.
当时她...她就坐在后面...
She was... she was sitting back there...
不  不是  当时她手里拿着一个三明治站在后面
No, no, she was standing back there with a sandwich in her hand
还有她说她得早点去睡觉
And she said she had to go to sleep early
因为她还得开很远的路程
Because she had a long drive ahead of her.
-后面?  -回她要回的地方啊
- Back where? - Back where she came from.
不是  你之前说她坐在后面...
No, you said before that she was sitting back there...
站在后面...
Standing back there...
是的  我后面的客厅里
Yes, back in my parlor there.
她很饿  然后我就给她做了个三明治
She was very hungry and I made her a sandwich
然后她说她很累就直接去睡了
And then she said that she was tired and she had to go right to bed.
-明白  她付现金还是支票?  -现金
- I see. How did she pay you? Cash? Check? - Cash.
现金
Cash, huh?
她离开之后  就没回来了吗
And after she left, she didn't come back?
她为什么要回来呢
Well, why should she?
我想就这么多了  阿伯盖斯特先生
Well, Mr. Arbogast, I guess that's about it.
如果你不介意的话  我先去忙了
I've got some work to do, if you don't mind.
说实话  我介意
Well, to tell you the truth, I do mind.
如果做肉冻缺了凝结剂的话  就没法凝结
You see, if it doesn't jell, it isn't aspic, and this ain't jelling.
就做不成肉冻  缺一不可
It's not coming together. Something's missing.
我不知道你期望我告诉你些什么
Well, I don't know what you could expect me to know.
人们来来往往
People just come and go, you know.
对  她不是还在这儿吧
That's right. She isn't still here, is she?
不在了
No.
如果我想要检查所有的房间
If I wanted to check the cabins, all 12 of them,
我是不是需要搜查令呀
I'd need a warrant, wouldn't I?
如果你不信的话  就跟我来吧
Listen, if you don't believe me, come on with me.
你可以帮我换床单
You can help me change beds.
不用了  多谢
Okay? Oh. no, thanks.
改变主意了?
Change your mind?
我...我想肯定是因为我的某些表情
You know, I... I think I must have one of those faces you just can't
使得你不相信我的话
Help believing.
-还有人在家吗  -没有
- Is anyone at home? - No.
是吗  那儿有人坐在窗户旁边
Oh? There's somebody sitting up in the window.
没  没有
No, no, there isn't.
肯定有  你去瞧瞧
Sure, go ahead. Take a look.
那肯定是我母亲
Oh, that must be my mother.
她是个病人
She's an invalid.
实际上  她喜欢独居
It's practically like living alone.
明白
Oh, I see.
如果这个女孩  曼璐・克兰在这儿
Now, if this girl, Marion Crane, were here, you wouldn't
你不会把她藏起来吧
Be hiding her, would you?
-不会  -即使她出高价也不会吗
- No. - Not even if she paid you well?
不会
No.
我们这样说好了  我不想跟你争论
Let's just say, just for the sake of argument,
她想要你勇敢地保护她
That she wanted you to gallantly protect her.
你知道你被利用了
You'd know that you were being used.
你不会蠢到被耍吧
You wouldn't be made a fool of, would you?
但我并不傻  我...
But I'm not a fool. well, I...
我不能被别人愚弄  即便是被女人耍
And I'm not capable of being fooled, not even by a woman.
这不是在诋毁你的男子气概
Well, this is not a slur on your manhood.
这么说吧
Let's put it this way.
她可能耍了我  但她没有耍我的母亲
She might have fooled me, but she didn't fool my mother.
那你母亲见过她了?  我可以跟你母亲谈一下吗
Well, then your mother met her. Could I talk to your mother?
不行  如我之前跟你说的  她不见外人
No. As I told you, she's confined.
知道  但就几分钟而已
Yes, but just for a few minutes. That's all.
可能会有你所遗漏的线索
There might be some hint that you missed out on.
生病的老女人通常比较易怒
You know, sick old women are usually pretty sharp.
阿伯盖斯特先生...我想我已经...
Mr. Arbogast... I think I've...
就一会儿  我不会触怒她的
Just for a moment. I wouldn't disturb her.
我想我已经都跟你说清楚了
I think I've talked to you all I want to.
知道  但就...
Yes, but just for...
我想如果你马上离开就再好不过了  谢谢
I think it'd be much better if you left now. Thanks.
好吧
Well, all right.
如果你让我跟她谈一下肯定会让我少走很多冤枉路
You sure would save me a lot of leg work if you'd let me talk to her.
这也需要搜查令吗
Would I need a warrant for that, too?
当然
Sure.
好吧  不管怎样还是谢谢
All right. Thanks anyway.
喂  卢密斯  我是阿伯盖斯特  莱拉在吗
Hello, Loomis. This is Arbogast. Is Lila there?
好  请让她听电话
Okay. Let me talk to her, please.
喂  莱拉
Hello, Lila.
听着  莱拉  曼璐来过这儿
Lila, listen. Marion was up here.
是的  上个星期六晚上她在贝茨汽车旅馆投宿
Yes, she spent last Saturday night at the Bates Motel.
就在旧公路旁边
It's right out here on the old highway.
我连她住哪个房间都知道  是1号房
I even know what cabin she was in. It was number one.
这个年轻的旅馆老板说她只住了一晚
This young fella that runs the place said that she just spent the night,
第二天就离开了  就这样
Left the next day and that was it.
还不大确定
No, not exactly.
相信我  我确实盘问过他
Well, I did question him, believe me,
但我认为我这趟没白来
But I think I got all there was to get.
我还得从这儿找点线索
I'll just have to pick up the pieces from here.
说实话  我感觉不是很满意...
Well, I tell you, I don't feel entirely satisfied...
这个小伙子有个生病的老母亲
See, this boy had a sick old mother.
我想她见过曼璐并跟她说过话
I think she saw Marion and talked to her.
没有  遗憾地是他不让我见她
No. No, unfortunately, he wouldn't let me see her.
我有  但我想会先回汽车旅馆
Well, I was, but I think I'll go back to the motel first.
不用  你跟卢密斯待一起  我大概1小时内回去
No, you stay there with Loomis. I'll be back in about an hour.
好的  听着  我...
All right, fine. Listen, I...
你知道我的想法会很高兴的
You'll be happy to know what I think.
我想我们的朋友萨姆・卢密斯并不知道曼璐来这儿
I think our friend Sam Loomis didn't know that Marion was here.
好的  大概1小时左右见
Yeah. all right. See you in about an hour or less.
好的  再见
All right, bye bye.
贝茨?
Bates?
有时寂寞的声音会萦绕在周六的夜晚
Sometimes Saturday night has a lonely sound.
有留意过吗  莱拉
Ever notice that, Lila?
萨姆  他说1小时左右
Sam, he said an hour or less.
对
Yeah.
已经过去3个小时了
It's been three.
难道我们就这样坐着干等吗
Well, are we just going to sit here and wait?
他会回来的
He'll be back.
耐心等待吧
Let's sit still and hang on, okay?
旧公路有多远?
How far is the old highway?
你不会想要出去吧
You wanna go out there, don't you?
-找阿伯盖斯特跟那个老太太算账...  -是的
- Bust in on Arbogast and the old lady... - Yes.
-或许摇醒她  -是的
- Maybe shake her up. - Yes!
那可不是什么理智的行为
That wouldn't be a wise thing to do.
在我的家族字典里没有耐心两字
Patience doesn't run in my family, Sam.
-我要出去  -听着  阿伯盖斯特说过...
- I'm going out there. - Look, Arbogast said...
1个小时左右嘛
An hour, or less.
我走了
Well, I'm going.
你会迷路的
You'll never find it.
待在这儿
Stay here.
为什么我不可以跟你一起去
Why can't I go with you?
不知道  我们其中一个得留下
I don't know. One of us has to be here,
说不定他已经在路上了
In case he's on the way.
我该做些什么  就这样坐着干等吗
What am I supposed to do, just sit here and wait?
对  待在这儿
Yeah. stay here.
阿伯盖斯特?
Arbogast?
Arbogast!
阿伯盖斯特?
他还没回来吗
He didn't come back here?
萨姆
Sam!
阿伯盖斯特跟贝茨都不在  只有一个老太太在家
No Arbogast, no Bates. Only the old lady at home.
病老太没法应门  或是不愿应门
Sick old lady unable to answer the door, or unwilling.
他会去哪儿了呢
Where could he have gone?
也许他找到了一些确切的线索
Maybe he got some definite lead.
就直奔线索而去了
Maybe he went right on.
不知会我一声?
Without calling me?
走得太急了
In a hurry.
萨姆  当时他什么线索都没有就打来了
Sam, he called when he had nothing.
什么都没  除了一股不满意的感觉
Nothing but a dissatisfied feeling.
你不认为如果他发现了什么会打给我们吗
Don't you think he'd have called if he had anything at all?
是的  我想他会打来
Yes, I think he would've.
我们去见艾尔・钱伯斯吧
Let's go see Al Chambers.
他是谁
Who's he?
我们这儿的副警长
Our deputy sheriff around here.
好的  我去拿外套
All right. Let me get my coat.
晚上好
Good evening.
不知道该从何说起  直接切入主题吧
Well, I don't know where to start, except at the beginning.
好
Yes.
这位是来自凤凰城的莱拉・克兰
This is Lila Crane from Phoenix.
你好
How do you do?
她来这儿是为了找她妹妹的
She's been here searching for her sister.
请了一位私家侦探帮忙...
There's this private detective helping and...
我们接到那个私家侦探打来的电话
Well, we got a call from this detective
说他在那家旧公路旁的汽车旅馆追查到她的消息
Saying that he'd traced her to that motel out on the old highway.
那肯定是贝茨汽车旅馆
That must be the Bates Motel.
他查到她住过那儿
He traced her there
然后打给我们说他要去盘问贝茨太太
and called us to say he was going to question Mrs.Bates.
诺曼结婚了?
Norman took a wife?
不是  我想没有  是位老太太  他的母亲
No, I don't think so. An old woman. His mother.
不管是谁  自从挂完电话后
Well, anyway, that was early this evening.
我们就跟他失去了联系
We haven't seen or heard from him since.
你妹妹失踪多久了
Now, your sister's missing how long?
到昨天为止  她已经失踪1个星期了
Well, she left Phoenix a week ago yesterday, without a trace.
你跟那位侦探怎么会追查到菲尔威尔的
How'd you and this detective come to trace her to Fairvale?
他们以为她来找我了
They thought she'd be coming to me.
她是独自离开凤凰城的吗
Left Phoenix under her own steam?
是的
Yes.
她不像是失踪倒像是逃跑
She's not missing so much as she's run away.
对
That's right.
为什么
From what?
她偷了些钱
She stole some money.
很多吗
A lot?
4万块钱
$40,000.
那警方没有...
And the police haven't been able to...
大家考虑到...
Everyone concerned thought
如果他们能让她把钱还回去的话
If they could get her to give the money back,
他们可以避免她被抓进警局
They could avoid involving her with the police.
所以才请私家侦探
That explains the private detective.
他追查到她曾住在贝茨旅馆
He traced her to the Bates place.
他打电话给你具体说了些什么
What exactly did he say when he called you?
他说曼璐在那儿住了一晚就走了
Well, he said that Marion was there for one night and then she left.
带着4万块钱?
With the $40,000?
钱的事他只字未提
Well, he didn't say anything about the money.
电话内容无关紧要  是吗
It isn't important what he said on the phone, is it?
在他跟那位母亲谈完话之后
He was supposed to come back here and talk to us
他本该回到这儿跟我们碰面  但他并没回来
After he talked to the mother, and he didn't.
所以我才找你介入调查此事
That's what I want you to do something about.
调查什么
Like what?
抱歉我说话急了点
I'm sorry if I seem overanxious.
只是我敢肯定那儿
It's just that I'm sure there's
有什么不对劲  并且我必须调查清楚
something wrong out there and I have to know what.
我也觉得那儿不对劲
Well, I think there's something wrong too, Miss,
但不是同一件事
but not the same thing.
我想不对劲的是你的私家侦探
I think what's wrong is your private detective.
我想他可能从诺曼・贝茨那儿
I think he got himself a hot lead as to where your sister was going,
知道你妹妹去向的重要线索
Probably from Norman Bates,
然后打给你  让你们继续等消息
And called you to keep you still
而他就出发去追她和钱
While he took off after her and the money.
不会的  他说他还没调查清楚会再回来
No, no, he said he was dissatisfied and he was going back there.
为什么不打给诺曼  问他说到底发生了什么事
Why don't you call Norman and let him say just what happened?
现在吗
At this hour?
我刚从那儿回来  他出去了
Well, he was out when I was there just a while ago.
如果他回来了  可能还没睡
If he's back, he probably isn't even in bed yet.
你去的时候他在家
He wasn't out when you were there,
夜阑人静
He just wasn't
像某些人一样  不应门罢了
answering the door in the dead of night, like some people do.
这个小伙子像位隐士
This fellow lives like a hermit.
你肯定还记得10年前发生的那件不幸的事
You must remember that bad business out there about 10 years ago.
求你打一下吧
Please. Call.
弗洛里  警长让你连线贝茨汽车旅馆
Florrie, the Sheriff wants you to connect him with the Bates Motel.
喂  是诺曼吗  我是钱伯斯警长
Hello, Norman? Sheriff Chambers.
我很好  谢谢
I've been just fine, thanks.
听着  我们这儿出了点事
Listen, we got worries here.
今晚是否有个男的去过你那儿
Yeah, have you had a fella stop by there tonight...
他不是来投宿的
Well, this one wouldn't be a customer, anyway.
他是位私家侦探  名字叫...
He's a private detective, name of...
阿伯盖斯特
Arbogast.
叫阿伯盖斯特
他离开之后呢
And after he left?
没关系  诺曼
No, that's okay, Norman.
这位侦探去过那儿  诺曼跟他讲了那个女孩的事
This detective was there, Norman told him about the girl,
侦探谢过他之后就走了
The detective thanked him and he went away.
他没再回去吗  他没去见那位母亲吗
And he didn't come back? He didn't see the mother?
你的侦探告诉你  他不能马上回来
Your detective told you he couldn't come right back
因为他要去盘问诺曼・贝茨的母亲  是吗
Because he was going to question Norman Bates's mother, right?
是的
Yes.
诺曼・贝茨的母亲10年前就去世了
Norman Bates's mother has been dead and buried
并安葬在绿色草坪墓地
In Green Lawn cemetery for the past 10 years.
她被安葬时所穿的寿衣还是我帮诺曼选的
I helped Norman pick out the dress she was buried in.
浅紫光蓝色
Periwinkle blue.
那不只是地方历史事件
It ain't only local history, Sam.
也是菲尔威尔地区唯一一起谋杀跟自杀案
It's the only case of murder and suicide on Fairvale Ledgers.
当贝茨太太发现跟她交往的家伙已有家室
Mrs. Bates poisoned this guy she was involved with
她就把他毒死了
When she found out he was married.
然后她也服毒自杀了
Then took a helping of the same stuff herself.
是番木鳖碱  死得很难看
Strychnine. Ugly way to die.
诺曼发现他们死在一起
Norman found them dead together.
在床上
In bed.
你是说我见到的那个坐在窗边的老妇人
You mean that old woman I saw sitting in the window out there wasn't
不是贝茨的母亲吗
Bates' mother?
等等  萨姆  你肯定见过一位老妇人吗
Now, wait a minute, Sam. Are you sure you saw an old woman?
是的  在汽车旅馆后面的房子里
Yes! In the house behind the motel!
我去叫门  但她根本不理我
I called and pounded but she just ignored me!
你是想告诉我  你见到了诺曼・贝茨的母亲  对吗
You want to tell me you saw Norman Bates' mother?
但她肯定是  因为阿伯盖斯特也这么说
But it had to be because Arbogast said so, too!
那个年轻人不让他去见她  是因为她病得很重
And the young man wouldn't let him see her because she was too ill.
好吧  如果那位妇人是贝茨太太
Well, if the woman up there is Mrs. Bates,
那埋在绿草坪墓地的又是谁呢
Who's that woman buried out in Green Lawn cemetery?
母亲  我现在要提出...
Now, mother, I'm gonna bring something up...
抱歉  孩子
I am sorry, boy,
但你命令我时  看起来确实很可笑
But you do manage to look ludicrous when you give me orders.
求您了  母亲
Please, mother.
不行  我不会藏在果窖里
No! I will not hide in the fruit cellar.
你觉得我疯了  对吗
You think I'm fruity, huh?
我就待在这儿
I'm staying right here.
这是我的房间  谁也别想把我赶走
This is my room and no one will drag me out of it,
我无耻的儿子更不行
Least of all my big, bold son.
他们会来这儿的  母亲
They'll come now, mother.
他跟踪过那个姑娘  现在有人要跟踪他
He came after the girl, and now someone will come after him.
母亲  求您了  几天就好
Mother, please, it's just for a few days.
这样他们就找不到您了
Just for a few days so they won't find you.
几天就好吗
Just for a few days?
在这阴暗潮湿的果窖?  决不
In that dark, dank fruit cellar? No!
你曾把我藏在那里  孩子  你休想再让我去那儿了  绝不
You hid me there once, boy, and you won't do it again, not ever again!
现在滚蛋
Now get out!
我让你滚蛋  小子
I told you to get out, boy.
我把您抱下去  母亲
I'll carry you, mother.
诺曼  你想干什么
Norman, what do you think you're doing?
别碰我  诺曼
Don't you touch me! Don't! Norman!
把我放下  放下我  我自己能走
Put me down! Put me down! I can walk on my own.
早上好  早上好
Good morning. Good morning.
早上好
Good morning.
如果您不介意  我们愿驾车带您去那间旅馆
We thought if you didn't mind, we'd drive out to that motel with you.
他已经去过了
He's already been.
在仪式之前离开的
Went out before service.
你们俩吃过早餐了吗
Did you two have breakfast?
什么也没发现吗
You didn't find anything?
没有  我们别挡道
Nothing. Let's clear the way here.
他说了什么关于我妹妹的事吗
Well, what did he say about my sister?
和他向你的侦探说的一样  她用了匿名
Just what he told your detective, she used a fake name.
我看过了登记簿
Saw the register myself.
看过了整个地方  事实上  那小伙子一个人住在那儿
Saw the whole place, as a matter of fact. That boy's alone there.
他母亲不在吗
No mother?
肯定是你的幻觉  萨姆
You must have seen an illusion, Sam.
我知道你不会产生幻觉
I know you're not the seeing illusion's type,
但那儿没有女人  而且我不相信鬼神之说
But no woman was there and I don't believe in ghosts,
-就是这样  -我仍然觉得那儿有...
- So there it is. - I still feel that there's something...
我理解你的感受  很抱歉不能让你好受些
Can see you do. I'm sorry l couldn't make you feel better.
你今天下午来我办公室
You want to come around to my office this afternoon
填一份失踪人口及遭遇抢劫的报告  这才是你要做的
And report a missing person and a theft, that's what you want to do.
你越快把此事交由法办
The sooner you drop this in the lap of the law,
就越有可能快点找到你妹妹
That's the sooner you stand a chance of your sister being picked up.
怎么样
How about that?
我不知道
I don't know.
今天是周日
It's Sunday.
晚饭时来我家填报告吧
Come on over to the house and do your reporting around dinnertime.
这样会比较好
It'll make it nicer.
你也来吧  萨姆
You too, Sam.
谢谢
Thank you.
也许我真的会产生幻觉
Maybe I am the seeing illusions type.
不  你不会
No, you're not.
好吧  你想让我把你送回旅馆还是...
Well, you want me to drop you at the hotel or...
萨姆
Sam.
在没亲自去过那里之前  我不会罢休的
I still won't feel satisfied until I go out there.
我也不会  走吧
Neither will I. Come on.
我们最好想想到了那儿要怎么做
We better decide what we're gonna say or do when we walk in there.
我们先去注册结婚
We're going to register as man and wife.
再去他那儿租间房
We're going to get shown to a cabin,
之后我们要调查那儿的每个角落  从里到外
And then we're going to search every inch of the place, inside and out.
我想知道诺曼・贝茨在哪儿隐居
I wonder where Norman Bates does his hermiting.
有人在窗户那儿  我看到窗帘动了
Someone's at that window. I just saw the curtain move.
过来
Come on.
什么事
Well?
正想给你打电话
Just coming up to ring for you.
我猜你们想住店
Suppose you want a room.
我们本想直接去旧金山
We were gonna try to make it straight to San Francisco,
但是我们看了看天
But we don't like the look of that sky.
感觉马上要变天了  对吧
Looks like a bad day coming, doesn't it?
好吧
Okay.
我带你们去10号房间
I'll take you to cabin 10.
我们最好还是先登记  对吧
Better sign in first, hadn't we?
不  没必要
No. That's not necessary.
我的老板会为此次旅行买单  90%可以报销
My boss is paying for this trip and, well, it's 90% business.
但他需要正式发票
He wants practically notarized receipts.
我们最好登记  并拿到发票
I'd better sign in and get a receipt.
谢谢
Thank you.
-我帮你们去拿行李  -我们没行李
- I'll get your bags. - Haven't any.
那我带你们看一下房间
I'll show you the room, then.
头回看到你这么开旅店
First time I've ever seen it happen.
在美国的其他旅店  没有行李的旅客必须登记
You check in any other place in this country without bags
而且要付定金
And you have to pay in advance.
10美元
$10.
我的发票
That receipt.
我先去看看
I'll go on ahead.
好了  这是您的发票  那么  我来给您带路
All right, there's your receipt. Now, I'll show you the cabin.
不麻烦了  我们自己能找到
Don't bother yourself. We'll find it.
萨姆  我们必须去调查那个房间
Sam, we have to go into that cabin and search it,
无论我们多么害怕  或者付出多大代价
No matter what we're afraid of finding or how much it may hurt.
知道了
I know.
如果真有事  你觉得那儿会是事发地点吗
Do you think if something happened, it happened there?
我不知道
I don't know.
但如果你有一家这样不赚钱的旅店
But if you had a useless business like this motel,
需要什么把它脱手
What would you need to get out?
然后在别的地方再开一家新的呢
To get a new business somewhere else?
4万块钱?
$40,000?
你如何证明这点
How could we prove that...
如果他在新高速路上开了家汽车旅店  一年后...
Well, if he opens a motel on the new highway in, say, a year...
这儿一定有证据
There must be some proof that exists now,
一定有能证明他抢走了曼璐钱的证据
Something that proves he got that money away from Marion somehow.
你凭什么那么肯定
What makes you sound so certain?
阿伯盖斯特  她喜欢我  萨姆
Arbogast. He liked me, Sam.
或者他对我感到愧疚  对你
Or he felt sorry for me and he was
他亦是如此
Beginning to feel the same way about you.
从上次和他通话就可以证明
I could tell the last time I talked to him on the phone.
在去任何地方  或是作任何事情前
He wouldn't have gone anywhere
他一定会通知我们  除非有人阻止了他
Or done anything without telling us, unless he was stopped.
如果有人阻止了他  说明他一定发现了什么
And he was stopped. So he must have found out something.
我们从1号房间开始调查
We'll start with cabin one.
如果他看到我们  咱们就假装在散步
If he sees us, we're just taking the air.
贝茨
Bates.
-没有浴帘  -萨姆
- No shower curtain. - Sam!
看  这是什么
Look! What is it?
是数字  它没被冲掉  看
It's figuring. It didn't get washed down. Look.
一些数字是用4万加减得来的
Some figure has been added to or subtracted from 40,000.
这证明曼璐来过这儿
That proves Marion was here.
这太巧了
It'd be too wild a coincidence...
贝茨从未否认她来过这儿
Bates never denied she was here.
这不能证明他找到了那些钱吗
Well, doesn't that prove that he found out about the money?
我们要直接去问他把钱藏哪儿了吗
Do we simply ask him where he's hidden it?
不
No.
但那老妇人  无论她是谁  她曾告诉过阿伯盖斯特一些事
But that old woman, whoever she is, she told Arbogast something.
我想让她也把那些告诉我们
I want her to tell us the same thing.
你不能上去
You can't go up there.
为什么
Why not?
-因为贝茨  -那我们去找他
- Bates. - Well, let's find him.
我们其中一人把他稳住  另一人去找那位老妇人
One of us can keep him occupied while the other gets to the old woman.
如果他不愿意　你一定稳不住他
You'll never be able to hold him still if he doesn't want to be held.
我不想让你独自去他的房间
I don't like you going into that house alone.
但我能应付那个老病妇
I can handle a sick old woman.
好吧　我去把贝茨稳住
All right, I'll find bates and keep him occupied.
等等
Wait a minute.
如果你从那妇人嘴里得知了什么后
If you get anything out of the mother,
能找到回城的路吗
Can you find your way back to town?
是的　当然
Yes, of course.
如果你真的得到了重要证据　不必来通知我
If you do get anything, don't stop to tell me.
你在找我吗
You looking for me?
-什么事　-是的　事实上
- Why - Yes, as a matter of fact.
我的妻子在睡觉
Wife's taking a nap
但我可能会吵到她
And I never can keep quiet enough for her,
所以我来找你聊聊天
So I just thought I'd look you up and talk.
很好　你对房间还满意吗
Good. You satisfied with your cabin?
很好
Oh, it's fine.
这么半天　都是我在讲话　对吧
I've been doing all the talking so far, haven't I?
我原本认为总是独处的人
I thought it was the people who were alone most of the time
一旦有谈话的机会　会滔滔不绝
Who did all the talking when they got the chance.
而你却一言不发
Here you are doing all the listening.
你一个人住在这儿　对吧
You are alone here, aren't you?
这会让我发疯的
Drive me crazy.
我觉得你的反应太极端了　对吧
I think that would be a rather extreme reaction, don't you?
这只是种修辞手法
Just an expression.
我是说　无论如何我也会离开
What I meant was I'd do just about anything to get away.
-你不会吗　-不会
- Wouldn't you? - No.
贝茨太太?
Mrs. Bates?
我不是说你住在这里不应该感到满足
I'm not saying you shouldn't be contented here,
我只是不敢相信你会很满足
I'm just doubting that you are.
我觉得如果你有机会摆脱困境  你肯定会
I think if you saw a chance to get out from under, you.
把这旅店脱手
Do unload this place.
这里吗  这旅店是我的全部
This place? This place happens to be my only world.
我在这里长大  在这里度过了快乐的童年
I grew up in that house up there. I had a very happy childhood.
我和母亲生活的非常幸福
My mother and I were more than happy.
你害怕了  是我的话让你害怕了吗
You look frightened. Have I been saying something frightening?
我不知道你在说些什么
I don't know what you.ve been saying.
我在说你母亲  还有你的汽车旅馆
I've been talking about your mother, about your motel.
你要如何处理它
How you gonna do it?
处理什么
Do what?
去个新地方再买一家吗  这样你就不必藏起你的母亲了
Buy a new one in a new town where you won't have to hide your mother.
请你立刻开车离开这儿  好吗
Why don't you just get in your car and drive away from here, okay?
你哪儿来的钱去做那些  贝茨
Where will you get the money to do that, Bates?
你是否已经把钱存起来了
Or do you already have it socked away?
闭嘴
Shut up!
很多钱  4万块钱
A lot of it. $40,000.
我打赌你妈妈知道钱在哪儿  也知道钱是怎么来的
I bet your mother knows where the money is and what you did to get it.
我想她会告诉我们的
I think she'll tell us.
跟你一起来的女孩呢  她在哪儿
Where's that girl you came here with? Where is she?
贝茨太太
Mrs. Bates...
我就是诺曼・贝茨
I'm Norman Bates!
如果谁能猜到答案  那他一定能当心理学家了
If anyone gets any answers it'll be the psychiatrist.
就连我也搞不懂他  而且他还认识我
Even I couldn't get to Norman and he knows me.
-你不冷吗  小姐  -不冷
- You warm enough, miss? - Yes.
他跟你谈过了吗
Did he talk to you?
没有
No.
我得知了一切  但不是从诺曼那里  是从他妈妈那儿
I got the whole story, but not from Norman. I got it from his mother.
诺曼・贝茨已经不存在了
Norman Bates no longer exists.
他本来还有一半尚存
He only half existed to begin with.
现在另一半完全占据了他
And now the other half has taken over,
或许一直如此
Probably for all time.
是他杀了我妹妹吗
Did he kill my sister?
是
Yes.
也不是
And no.
听着  如果你想为我们打精神病学的铺垫
Well, now look, if you're trying to lay some psychiatric groundwork
这位伙计更愿意去抓...
For some sort of plea, this fellow would like to cop...
精神病学家不做任何铺垫
A psychiatrist doesn't lay the groundwork.
他们仅仅想解释缘由
He merely tries to explain it.
-但我妹妹...  -是啊
- But my sister is... - Yes.
是啊  我很遗憾
Yes, I'm sorry.
你的私家侦探也很遗憾
The private investigator, too.
如果你去调查汽车旅馆附近的沼泽  你就会...
If you drag that swamp somewhere in the vicinity of the motel, you'll...
你是否有失踪人口案件仍然在册
Have you any unsolved missing persons cases on your books?
是的  有两个
Yes, two.
都是年轻女孩吗
Young girls?
他是不是已经承认...
Did he confess to...
-就像我说的  -那位母亲
- Like I said, - The mother.
现在  我从他母亲那儿得到信息的方式是这样的
Now, to understand it the way I understood it, hearing it from the mother,
说道诺曼人格中母亲的那部分
That is, from the mother half of Norman's mind,
我们须从10年前谈起
You have to go back 10 years
那时  诺曼杀了他的母亲及她的情人
To the time when Norman murdered his mother and her lover.
自从他父亲去世后
Now, he was already dangerously disturbed,
他的精神就极度紊乱了
Had been ever since his father died.
他的母亲  是一位执着而且苛刻的女性
His mother was a clinging, demanding woman,
他们两个多年来就好像生活在
And for years the two of them lived
没有其他人的世界里
As if there was no one else in the world.
然后  她爱上了一个男人
Then she met a man,
对于诺曼  感觉就像她为了那个男人把自己抛弃了
And it seemed to Norman that she threw him over for this man.
这让他无法忍受  最终将二人全部杀死
Now, that pushed him over the line and he killed them both.
弑母大概是最无法令人忍受的犯罪了
Matricide is probably the most unbearable crime of all,
尤其是儿子亲手杀了母亲
Most unbearable to the son who commits it.
因此  他必须洗清罪恶  至少在他的思想中要这样
So he had to erase the crime, at least in his own mind.
他偷走了她的尸体
He stole her corpse.
棺材下葬时装的是其他重物
A weighted coffin was buried.
他把尸体藏在了果窖
He hid the body in the fruit cellar,
并十分妥善地保存着它
Even treated it to keep it as well as it would keep.
但这还不够
And that still wasn't enough.
她人虽在那里  但却成了一具尸体
She was there, but she was a corpse.
所以他开始以母亲的方式思考  说话
So he began to think and speak for her,
可以说  他把自己的一半给了他母亲
Give her half his life, so to speak.
有时  他的两种人格同时存在  可以形成对话
At times he could be both personalities, carry on conversations.
而其他的时候  他母亲的人格完全占据了他
At other times, the mother half took over completely.
他再也不完全是诺曼了  大部分时间他是自己的母亲
He was never all Norman, but he was often only mother,
因为他是如此病态地妒忌着自己的母亲
And because he was so pathologically jealous of her,
所以他认为母亲也同样妒忌着他
He assumed that she was as jealous of him.
因此  如果他被其他女人深深吸引
Therefore, if he felt a strong attraction to any other woman,
他"母亲"的一面就会发狂
The mother side of him would go wild.
当他遇到你妹妹时
When he met your sister,
就被她深深触动  深深吸引
He was touched by her, aroused by her.
他想要她
He wanted her.
这激怒了他"母亲"的一面  然后他"母亲"杀了那姑娘
That set off the jealous mother, and mother killed the girl.
杀完人后  诺曼如梦方醒
After the murder, Norman returned as if from a deep sleep,
变回了那个忠诚的儿子  并掩盖掉一切罪行
And, like a dutiful son, covered up all traces of the crime
他确信杀人的是他母亲
He was convinced his mother had committed!
他为什么要穿成那样
Why was he dressed like that?
他是个异装癖
He's a transvestite.
并不确切
Not exactly.
为了达到改变性别或者自我满足
A man who dresses in women's clothing in order to achieve a sexual change
而穿上女人服饰的男人被称作异装癖
Or satisfaction is a transvestite.
但对于诺曼而言  他只是想竭尽全力去维持
But in Norman's case, he was simply doing everything possible
自己母亲还活着的这一幻觉
To keep alive the illusion of his mother being alive.
而当现实逼近时
And when reality came too close,
当危险或者欲望要吞噬这个幻觉时
When danger or desire threatened that illusion,
他就会穿上女人服饰  甚至戴上假发
He'd dress up, even to a cheap wig he bought.
在屋子里徘徊  坐在母亲的椅子上  用母亲的腔调说话
He'd walk about the house, sit in her chair, speak in her voice.
他试着成为自己的母亲
He tried to be his mother.
现在  他做到了
And now he is.
这就是我说  是从他母亲那里得知一切的原因
That's what I meant when I said I got the story from the mother.
当人们脑海中出现双重人格时
You see, when the mind houses two personalities,
就一定会有冲突  甚至战争
There's always a conflict, a battle.
对于诺曼而言  战争已经结束
In Norman's case, the battle is over,
较为强势的人格获胜
And the dominant personality has won.
那4万块钱呢  谁拿走了
And the $40,000? Who got that?
在沼泽里  这次犯罪源于人格分裂  而非图财
The swamp. These were crimes of passion, not profit.
他觉得有点冷  我能把毯子给他吗
He feels a little chill. Can I bring him this blanket?
当然  可以
Oh, sure. All right.
谢谢
Thank you.
当一位母亲不得不谴责自己的儿子时
It's sad when a mother has to speak the words
是多么悲哀啊
That condemn her own son,
但我不会让他们认为是我杀的人
But I couldn't allow them to believe that I would commit murder,
他们会抛弃他的  就像我数年前应该做的那样
They'll put him away now, as I should have years ago,
他一向很坏
He was always bad,
最终  他打算告诉警察是我杀的那些女孩和那个男人
And in the end he intended to tell them I killed those girls and that man,
除了端坐和凝视外  我什么也做不了
As if I could do anything except just sit and stare,
就像他的标本鸟一样
Like one of his stuffed birds,
他们知道  我连手指都动不了  而且我也不会
They know I can't even move a finger, and I won't,
我只会在这里静静端坐  以免被人怀疑
I'll just sit here and be quiet, just in case they do suspect me,
他们大概会监视我  好吧  让他们看吧
They're probably watching me, well, let them,
让他们看看我是什么样的人
Let them see what kind of a person I am,
我甚至不会拍死这只苍蝇
I'm not even gonna swat that fly,
我希望他们在监视我  他们就会看到
I hope they are watching, they'll see,
他们会看到并且明白
They'll see and they'll know,
之后  他们会说"为什么  她连苍蝇都不愿伤害啊"
And they'll say, ''why, she wouldn't even harm a fly, ''